it's physically this is mm said this is
what hope really ought to be it's
physically in a place of being very very
much in relationship with what is real
right
but then choosing to orient towards it
in a nonreactive stance does it also
shift things so that choosing to orient
and an honor to like is hope
I like this I'm getting I'm getting a
visual image like if you sort of got
this right
fluid optimal grip on a complex
situation and it's predominantly this
way but because you actually have you're
really in touch you see a possibility
here and that your stance towards it
might actually afford that possibility
coming forth is it yes like that yeah
that's exactly it
and and this is key like again is it's
very it's a adducing it's a drawing out
if you try to if you try to teleport to
the end you're engaging in the magical
thinking that has often has claimed hope
yes yes yes very different right it's
that notion of one no it's like flow one
if I if I get back on my heels if I
second-guess myself if I assume the
worst
then I will destabilize my capacity I
would be out of balance I will no longer
be able to be in conformity conforming
with what's actually happening right and
then there's something like a again
because there's in back of it a sort of
metaphor it's the you know if you
imagine the surfer and the surfer is
seeing the spot like they see the pocket
in the wave breaking you might say they
hoped themselves into the spot right
right there's a combination of exactly
two things one is holding a
dispositional attitude of fluid balanced
relationship with what is in themselves
not holding themselves back a big piece
of this is not holding yourself back
right not getting in your head not
getting angry reactive and tightening up
and then seeking the best place to be
and orang2 yourself towards that best
place right like that's it
those are the two key components if you
have those two components therein lies
hope now reverse that say let's imagine
that's what Paul is
and see if that actually lands back on
faith so he says it's the hope of things
that are not yet seen and I guess it's
it would admit it would meet very nicely
especially if you go into the the the
Corinthian him towards agape where it
ends where he's proposing the most
excellent way by the way the way of
agape and then he proposes that in the
end we will know as we are knowing he
proposes a sort of a I suppose it's a
culmination a culmination of
participatory knowing we will know as we
are known right we will we will be in
complete conformity with ultimate
reality and so faith to use your your
metaphor is the hope that sees that as a
path as a way as a way that is
realizable
by a committed stance towards that
possibility is yeah that would work yeah
that's great
and that is great and this there's
something about that like okay so sir
check this out now I'm bringing in
Viktor Frankl of course it's great
established app let's bring him in bring
him in office up the sidelines no matter
where you are there is always hope which
is to say no matter where you are there
is always an appropriate dispositional
stance in relationship to where you are
there orient you towards the best
possibility of where you are yes yes
that's all we have to say right which is
a possibility in the sense of a
potentiality not just another not
logical possibility yeah and what was
interesting about Franco because if you
remember when he was talking about his
time in the camp he was very careful to
Sid this goes back to what we were
talking about the sweet spot he was very
careful to situate you know what he was
talking about with logos by the way
logotherapy
idea logos all connected right was right
how he differentiated between the two
groups that he saw worked able to
survive in the camps there were the
people who just gave up
and of course and they but there was
people who actually had the magical hope
they would say no no and they did
willful assertion we will be liberated
on day X I know it I know it and then
day X would come and of course the
liberation will not occur and then those
people were very very quickly fall apart
they would fall apart so it's not it's
not an assertion right this hope it's
something else it's I like your idea of
turning it into a verb a verb of
orientation and I see it almost like the
kind of reducing of possibilities that
then starts to afford a very nascent but
perhaps constantly accelerating
reciprocal opening yeah think of it like
like a child the child learning how to
do something yeah I learned how to stand
or to walk it's that thing it's like the
the feeling of the sense the sense of
what the the accomplishment of the
developmental growth is and the the
searching of all the different you know
a child learning how to walk like
lurching all over the place but in that
space of possibility there's a spot over
here that is the I know that is called
walking and by the way now we have an
integrity in there - yeah the
integration of all the distinct aspects
of self into an increasingly coherent
hold achieves a competency yeah and hope
is the orientation in that direction
right the correct by the way it's very
important right it's not a delusional is
a correct awareness of in fact the
presence and the orientation the
directionality and the proximity towards
that that location